A Man-eater.
食人者
Great. Better tell everyone quickly!
好樣的，最好趕快通知大家
-Captain! -Don't barge in--
-船長 -別闖進…
A Man-eater's attacking the ship! We need to go faster!
一隻食人者正在攻擊這艘船，我們得加速
What'd you say?
妳說什麼？
Sis, it's here!
姊，在這裡
Eat this!
吃我一顆子彈
Take that!
接招吧
Seriously?
不會吧？
TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
《天國大魔境》 （推動發車）
No one saw you, right?
沒人見到你吧？
Yup.
沒有
Then let's go! To see the babies!
那我們走吧，去看嬰兒
Here it is!
到了
Here?
這裡嗎？
-Follow me. -Huh?
-跟我來 -什麼？
We're going in through here!
從這裡進去喔
How am I supposed to do that?
我要怎麼上去啦？
KUKU
《玖玖》
Hey, did you hear that noise?
你們剛剛聽到怪聲了嗎？
I think so.
好像有喔
-Okay, watch this! -Quit it, you'll get hurt.
-好了，看我的厲害 -別這樣，你會受傷
Here goes.
開始囉
Abnormal behavior detected.
偵測到異常行為
Taka's always full of energy.
鷹總是這麼有活力
Close contact of more than ten seconds confirmed.
確認近距離接觸超過十秒鐘
Nanaki and Iwa again?
又是七貴和伊波？
I wonder what possessed them to kiss each other.
她們究竟是著了什麼魔 怎麼會想要接吻？
It's quite strange.
相當奇怪
We've never taught them that behavior.
我們從來沒教過這種行為
-Huh?
-怎麼了？
Possible deterioration in health detected.
偵側到健康狀況疑似惡化
Medical team, confirm Tarao's condition immediately.
醫療小組，請立刻確認多羅雄的狀況
The nurse is currently with him.
護士正在他身旁
We're on our way.
我們已經在路上了
Here, stick onto the wall.
像這樣把它黏在牆上
Okay. Go up.
好的，往上爬
What a good idea, Tokio!
真是個好主意耶，時男
This was Taka's idea.
這是鷹想到的
Let's go, Tokio!
來吧，時男
Let's look for it.
去找找看吧
Okay then…
好喔
Tokio!
時男
Hurry up.
快點
Right.
好
Am I going outside of the outside?
我現在正走向外面的外面嗎？
We're dead if it gets inside!
牠跑進來的話我們就死定了
Can't you shoot it away again?
小姐，妳就不能再朝牠開一槍嗎？
Then we can go and close all of the doors.
我們就能夠把所有的門關上
I can't. I'm out of bullets.
辦不到，子彈用光了
Don't know if the ship's lopsided or rusted,
不確定船是傾斜了還是生鏽了
but there's a door that won't budge.
有一扇門就是關不起來
Then the only thing we can do is barricade ourselves in here.
那我們也只能把這裡用障礙物封鎖起來
How long until we reach the shore?
還要多久才會靠岸？
Thirty minutes at top speed.
全速行駛的話要30分鐘
Will it hold?
支撐得了嗎？
Probably not.
恐怕是不行
Sis.
姊
From what I've seen, the fish uses those suction cup hands
就我看來，這條魚利用吸盤觸手
and a suit of water covering its body as a lubricant to move on land.
加上在身體覆蓋了一層水做為潤滑劑 讓牠得以在陸地上移動
It relies on the water suit to attack and move around.
它靠這層水膜來移動和攻擊
Where's the best place to fight it?
哪裡是最好的打鬥地點？
Somewhere it can't get water. On land?
讓牠不能接觸到水的地方，在陸地上？
Better if it's somewhere like a maze.
如果是像個迷宮的地方就更好了
Since it attacks and moves only in straight lines.
因為牠只能直線移動和直線攻擊
We'll fight it inside the ship.
我們就在船裡面跟牠決鬥
Inside the ship?
在船裡面？
Hey! There's a door downstairs, right?
嘿，下層甲板有一扇門，對吧？
Give me the key.
把鑰匙給我
DO NOT ENTER
（禁止進入）
Why?
憑什麼？
If you don't want to die, give it to me!
不想死的話，就把鑰匙給我
-It ain't locked! -Eh?
-門沒鎖 -什麼？
Ain't never been locked.
從來沒上鎖過
He said it ain't locked.
他說沒上鎖
Okay.
好的
Sis, wait!
姊，等等
How are we going to fight without the Kiru-Beam?
沒有貴留光線，我們要用什麼對付牠？
We have the Maru-Touch.
我們有小丸觸碰啊
And that is?
那是？
-You're going to kill it by touching it. -What?
你要用觸碰的方式殺死牠
Wait, you got no plan?
等等，妳完全沒有計畫？
Hey! Over here! Come and get me!
喂，過來這裡，來呀，來抓我呀
Here-- Here it comes!
牠…牠來了
Scary!
好可怕
Damn, the boxes!
可惡，這些箱子
Hurry and climb over!
快點爬過去
What an idiot! Dumb shot!
有夠白癡，亂射一通
Sis, it's open!
姊，門是開的
If you don't open both sides, the fish can't get in!
要同時打開兩側，魚才進得來
It doesn't need to come in!
牠根本不需要進來
-Yes, it does! -Huh?
-它就是需要進來 -什麼？
It's all boxes here too.
這裡也堆滿了箱子
Just get over there!
想辦法過去就對了
Damn! This isn't the best situation to come up with a plan!
可惡，這種狀況下，要怎麼制定戰略啦？
A door!
有一扇門
The door won't open. No way!
門打不開，完蛋了
Maru, you don't need to open it.
小丸，不用把門打開
Sis, it's no good. It won't open.
姊，狀況不妙，打不開
-I said it's okay. -Why?
-我說了不要緊 -怎麼會？
What's happening to it?
牠是怎麼搞的？
There should've been a ton of marijuana on this ship,
這艘船上應該載有一大堆大麻
but there were only vegetables upstairs.
但上層甲板只有蔬菜
I thought there'd be boxes of marijuana in this locked room.
所以我猜這個上鎖的房間 一定會有好幾箱大麻
With all the boxes and dried marijuana sucking up the water,
這些箱子再加上乾燥的大麻把水吸乾了
this guy's just a fish out of water.
這傢伙不過就是一條離水的魚
We won.
我們贏了
Looks fine. Go kill it.
狀況穩定，去把牠殺了吧
Beating it without the Kiru-Beam…
不靠貴留光線，要我宰了牠…
You can't just look at the opponent in these situations.
在這種狀況之下，你不能只盯著對手
You'll win if you stay calm and look at your surroundings.
你得保持冷靜，看向周邊環境
That's how I've survived.
我就是靠這點活下來的
Anyway, it's horrible.
總之，實在有夠糟糕
I can live with "Kiru-Beam," but "Maru-Touch" is just awful.
貴留光線我勉強接受 但小丸觸碰實在太爛了吧
-What're you talking about? -The stupid way you name things!
-你是什麼意思？ -妳很不會取名字
It's pitch black now.
現在漆黑一片
We're almost there. See?
我們快到了，你看
Okay. Nobody's around.
好的，周圍沒有人
Someone's in there sometimes?
有人會在那裡出沒嗎？
The Director, and adults I've never met.
園長和我從未見過的大人
Are we outside the school? Inside?
我在學校外面嗎？還是裡面？
Look!
你看
Real live babies.
活生生的嬰兒
Those are…
那些是…
babies?
嬰兒？
Intruder detected.
偵測到有人入侵
-Intruder detected. -Tokio!
-偵測到有人入侵 -時男
The sanctum. The sanctum.
昇殿室，昇殿室
Intruder detected. Intruder detected.
偵測到有人入侵，偵測到有人入侵
The sanctum.
昇殿室
What is this alert?
警報為何會響起？
SANCTUM
我不知道，我是第一次聽到
-It said intruder. -First, let's go in and see.
-它說有人入侵 -我們先進去看看再說吧
What is this fuss?
這是怎麼回事？
There was an intruder alert here!
偵測到這裡有人入侵
I also heard it.
我也聽到了
We will confirm it right now.
我們立刻確認
-Monitor Room. -We're looking into it, but…
-中控室 -我們正在調查，但是…
There's no sign of any intruder.
沒見到有人入侵的跡象
We'll continue our search, but it's most likely an error.
我們會繼續調查 但很有可能是警報器誤鳴
They didn't find us?
他們沒發現我們？
Tokio! Come on!
時男，快點
Hurry.
快點
Tokio!
時男
Okay, Mina.
好的，美娜
Yes.
什麼事？
Do you know anything about that alert?
你知道為什麼警報器會響嗎？
Isn't this place like a part of your body?
這個地方不就像是你身體的一部分嗎？
If a human had a health inspection,
如果一個人做了健康檢查
and received a report for "further examination required,"
檢查報告上面寫著「需要進一步檢查」
could that human identify where there was something wrong in their body?
那個人有辦法知道 他的身體是哪裡出了問題嗎？
I surrender, Mina. You win.
我投降，美娜，你贏了
Hold up!
喂，等等
You buggers! Where are you going after messing up our cargo?
你們這兩個蠢蛋， 把我們的貨物 弄得亂七八糟之後就想開溜？
If you hadn't been there, the whole ship would've been lost.
幸虧兩位在這裡，不然整艘船就不保了
You're our saviors. Thank you!
你們是我們的救星，謝謝
This is payment for the monster extermination.
這是消滅怪物的費用
We would've been killed if we hadn't fought back,
我們不反抗的話，也只有死路一條
so we can't take this.
我們不能收這筆錢
In exchange, tell us about this area.
與其付我們錢 不如跟我們介紹一下這個區域吧
Well…
這個嘛…
If you keep walking down this big road,
沿著這條大馬路一直走下去
you'll see a kind of town.
你們會見到一座城鎮
Really?
是喔？
Oh, yeah. Do you know anything about this logo?
對了，你們知道任何 關於這個標誌的事嗎？
Logos using birds have been around for ages,
用鳥做為標誌由來已久
so they all look the same to me.
對我來說，它們都是一個樣
-I see. -That logo!
-了解 -那個標誌！
You know it?
你知道什麼嗎？
It's…
那是…
Mitsuba's logo.
三葉的標誌
Mitsuba?
三葉？
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
對，我很肯定
You'll find a destroyed Mitsuba along this road.
沿著這條路走 你們會見到一間廢棄的三葉
Thanks!
多謝了
Hey, do you want to be our bodyguards?
你們想擔任我們的保鏢嗎？
We're busy right now, but one day!
我們現在很忙，以後再說吧
Damn brats, turning down my bro's offer.
該死的屁孩，竟敢拒絕老大的請求
They've got skills and character.
他們既有能耐又有個性
I'd like to see them again if the chance comes.
有機會的話我真想再見他們一面
They're good kids.
他們是好孩子
HOME CENTER
（居家用品中心）
Geez, that gangster. Getting my hopes up.
要死了，那個流氓給了我很大的希望
There's nothing here.
這裡什麼都沒有
-Sis! -Huh?
-姊 -怎麼了？
I found something we could eat!
我找到吃的了
Good job! Where was it?
太棒了，在哪裡？
It was in a bag under some shelves.
在層架下面的包包裡
I also found an umbrella. Should we go find the town?
我也找到了一把雨傘 我們該去找那座城鎮了嗎？
Nah, there's still time until sunrise. Let's sleep here.
先不用，距離天亮還有一段時間 在這裡睡一覺吧
HAYASE YOUKAN
（早瀨羊羹）
Youkan.
羊羹
Is this edible?
還可以吃嗎？
It's sweet!
好甜
You-kan! So you-can eat it!
用羊做的羹，可以吃的啦
So good! This is so good!
也太好吃了吧
It's hot!
好燙
We still have the ingredients, so I can make it again.
還有食材，想吃的話我可以再煮
Let's give it a name.
我們來取個名字吧
Since it's made with youkan and bread,
既然是用羊羹和麵包做的
how about "Bread-Kan Soup"?
叫麵包羹湯如何？
Right, the way you name things is the worst.
真是的，妳取名字的品味 怎麼會這麼糟糕？
You're the one who said "you-can eat" the youkan!
說出「用羊做的羹 可以吃的啦」這種話的人是你耶
Whatever its name, it's so good! How many more times can you make it?
不管叫什麼名字，好吃就好 妳還可以煮幾次？
Just once.
就只有一次
Only once…
只有一次啊…
But that was unexpected.
不過，那還真意想不到
The rain? Yeah, it came out of nowhere.
下雨嗎？對呀，突然就下起雨來了
No.
不是啦
Mitsuba.
三葉
You're right.
說的也是
What did he mean "I'm sure of it"?
他說的「我很肯定」是什麼意思啊？
It doesn't look like it at all. Idiot gangsters.
看起來完全不是那麼回事，白癡流氓
MITSUBA HOME CENTER
（三葉居家用品中心）
It's gone.
不見了
It should be here between these two dates.
應該在這兩個日期之間才對
I can't even remember it clearly.
我甚至完全記不得了
I should've burned it
我應該要把它
into the memory of my eyelids.
牢牢記在心上才對
-Okay! Let's play my new game! -Mimihime.
-好的，來玩我的新遊戲吧 -彌美姬
The only one who can play it is Taka.
會玩的人只有鷹
Hey.
嘿
-Just try it. -I'm going to the pool.
-試試看啦 -我要去泳池了
Picture?
相片？
I don't remember sending you any messages recently.
我不記得最近傳過任何訊息給你
I'd talk to you directly if I needed anything.
如果我需要什麼的話，會直接告訴你
-I see. -What kind of picture was it?
-是喔 -是怎樣的相片？
No-- That's not important.
沒有啦，那不重要
Actually…
是這樣的…
You might think I'm weird for saying this.
我這麼說可能會讓妳覺得我很奇怪
Every time I look at you,
我每次見到妳的時候
I get these wild urges.
都會出現莫名的衝動
What do you mean?
這是什麼意思？
Can you be more specific?
你可以說得明確一點嗎？
Specific…
明確一點嗎？
I want to…
我想要…
keep you in my room.
把妳關在我的房間裡
I don't mind if it's for a short while.
只有一下子的話我不介意喔
And what else?
還有呢？
Take off your clothes and touch you.
把妳的衣服脫光之後觸摸妳
To touch you,
觸摸妳
and lick… lick you.
還有舔妳
You want to eat me?
你想吃掉我嗎？
No! It's different from eating.
不是啦，跟吃東西不一樣啦
You'll disappear if I eat you.
如果我吃了妳，妳會消失
Do you want to cut me up and stab me with needles?
你想要把我切開，用針刺我嗎？
No way!
不是那樣啦
Hurry and get better, Tarao.
多羅雄，你要快點好起來喔
Let's play together again.
我們再一起玩
Tokio…
時男
It's okay. It's not an infectious disease.
不要緊，這種病不會傳染
That's not what I meant.
我沒有在擔心那個
Sorry.
抱歉
Tokio.
時男
What's wrong?
發生了什麼事？
Kona.
小奈
Have you calmed down?
你冷靜下來了嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
Everyone's acting weird these days.
這一陣子每個人的行為都怪怪的
It's so scary.
我好害怕
It's not something to be scared of.
沒有什麼好怕的
It's natural to fall in love with someone.
陷入愛河是很自然的事
One day, you'll also want to touch, and be touched by someone.
總有一天，你也會想要觸碰某個人 以及被那個人觸碰
There's no need to be confused by that.
沒有必要因為這種事感到困擾
Then--
那麼…
If that's the case…
如果是這樣的話
I'd like it to be Kona.
我希望那個人是小奈
I want it to be you too.
我也希望那個人是你
Tokio.
時男
This announcement is made only to your room.
這則廣播只有傳送到你房間
-Tarao's condition has suddenly changed. -What?
-多羅雄的狀況突然惡化了 -什麼？
Tarao wants to speak with you.
多羅雄有話想對你說
Come to the treatment room as soon as possible.
盡快趕到治療室
Tarao!
多羅雄
Leave us alone.
請讓我們單獨相處
Are you okay? Hang in there, Tarao!
你還好嗎？撐下去，多羅雄
We'll be outside. Call us if anything happens.
我們會待在外面 出現任何狀況的話馬上呼叫我們
Tarao.
多羅雄
Sorry.
對不起
It's okay. Hold my hand.
沒關係，握著我的手
I'm sorry about earlier.
先前的事我很抱歉
I didn't think about your feelings.
我沒顧慮到你的感受
Forget about that.
那件事就算了吧
I'm not going to get better.
我好不了了
Don't say that!
別說這種話
Listen to me, Tokio.
聽我說，時男
You need to…
你得要…
run away.
逃跑
This place is…
這個地方…
dangerous.
很危險